<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Center for Aquatic Biology and Aquaculture</title>
    <description>The Center for Aquatic Biology and Aquaculture (CABA) was established to provide leadership, focus, and support to University of California Davis researchers in addressing problems associated with California’s cultured and wild aquatic biological resources.
</description>
    <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://caba.ucdavis.edu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 20:50:50 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 20:50:50 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>CABA Scholarships for 2016 are available</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
Open to all UC Davis graduate students who are working on Fisheries Biology and/or Riparian or Limnetic Ecology research benefiting California&#39;s recreational fisheries. The CFFU scholarship is also open to junior and senior undergraduate students. Funds are awarded directly to the student and may be used for any research-related purpose, including supplies, travel, equipment, salary support, fees, etc.
For additional information and application package click &lt;a href=&quot;media/news/caba_scholarship_application_2016.doc&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Applications are due January 29 2016.
Please email completed applications to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jlboulanger@ucdavis.edu&quot;&gt;Joyce L Boulanger&lt;/a&gt; at jlboulanger@ucdavis.edu
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This year&#39;s available scholarships are:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;California Fly Fishers Unlimited (CFFU)&quot; src=&quot;/media//news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;California Fly Fishers Unlimited (CFFU), Bob Bittner Scholarship One $2,500 Scholarship&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen (DVFF)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen (DVFF), Bob Wisecarver Scholarship One $2,500 Scholarship &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Fly Fishers of Davis (FFD)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fly Fishers of Davis (FFD) Scholarship One $1,500 Scholarship&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Marin Rod and Gun Club (MRGC)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marin Rod and Gun Club (MRGC) Scholarships Two $2,000 Scholarships&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 15:58:42 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2016/01/07/CABA-Scholarships-for-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2016/01/07/CABA-Scholarships-for-2016/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Approaches for Responding to Climate Change in the San Francisco Bay-Delta</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image-left captioned image-inline&quot; src=&quot;/media/sfbay.png&quot; alt=&quot;SAC DELTA&quot; height=&quot;274&quot; width=&quot;364&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image-inline captioned image-inline&quot; src=&quot;/media/sfbay2.png&quot; alt=&quot;SAC DELTA2&quot; height=&quot;271&quot; width=&quot;361&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Video of this seminar is now available at the following link...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://ats.ucdavis.edu/ats-video/?kpid=0_om8kn2kn&quot;&gt;http://ats.ucdavis.edu/ats-video/?kpid=0_om8kn2kn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seminar Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Although climate change is one of many threats facing the San Francisco Bay-Delta region, it has the potential to dramatically alter ecosystem health and function on a vast scale. Among the challenges facing resource managers is to understand what the specific impacts will be and what the options are for managing the mitigation of those impacts. A range of strategies are under consideration for mitigating the impacts of sea level rise, changes in watershed inputs and changes in temperature, salinity and sediment loading. This process requires understanding the expected magnitude of change as well as the responses of different habitats to those changes.&lt;br /&gt;The goals of the seminar include updating current understanding of climate impacts based on the recent downscaled projections and information regarding the vulnerability and resilience of both natural and human environments. The most current approaches for climate adaptation and mitigation in response to climate related changes will be discussed. The overall goal is to synthesize ongoing efforts in order to facilitate efforts to develop a broader vision for the Bay-Delta ecosystem under future climate scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;image-inline captioned&quot; src=&quot;/media/caba.png&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image-inline captioned&quot; src=&quot;/media/delta.png&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image-inline captioned image-inline&quot; src=&quot;/media/coastal-institute.png&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This seminar is presented by UC Davis Center for Aquatic Biology and Aquaculture, Coastal and Marine Sciences Institute and the Delta Stewardship Council.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AGENDA:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;9:00 a.m.&lt;strong&gt; Welcome and Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Peter Goodwin, Delta Stewardship Council’s Delta Science Program&lt;br /&gt; Edwin Grosholz, University of California, Davis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;9:10 a.m.&lt;strong&gt; Climate change impacts on the Bay-Delta Ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; J&lt;em&gt;im Cloern, U.S. Geological Survey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;9:35 a.m.&lt;strong&gt; Projecting inundation in San Francisco Bay: Sea level rise and tides&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Mark Stacey, University of California, Berkeley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;10:00 a.m.&lt;strong&gt; Limitations of vertical marsh accretion rate as determined by suspended sediment concentration and sea-level rise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Jim Morris, University of South Carolina&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;10:25 a.m.&lt;strong&gt; Break&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;10:45 a.m.&lt;strong&gt; Carbon sequestration in natural and restored tidal wetlands in San Francisco Bay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; J&lt;em&gt;ohn Callaway, University of San Francisco&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;11:10 a.m.&lt;strong&gt; The Baylands and climate change: What we can do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Letitia Grenier, San Francisco Estuary Institute (SFEI)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;11:35 a.m.&lt;strong&gt; Update on SF Bay Living Shorelines and other Climate Adaptation pilot projects in SF Bay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Jeremy Lowe, Environmental Science Associates/SFEI&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;12:00 p.m.&lt;strong&gt; Lunch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1:15 p.m.&lt;strong&gt; Experiments with nature-based adaptation to increase the resiliency of social-ecological systems in the San Francisco Bay Estuary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Jeremy Lowe, Environmental Science Associates/SFEI&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1:40 p.m.&lt;strong&gt;  Landscape-scale planning for ecological resilience in the Delta&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Robin Grossinger, San Francisco Estuary Institute (SFEI)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2:05 p.m.&lt;strong&gt; Evolving views of permitting requirements for large scale shoreline modification projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Brad McCrea, San Francisco Bay Conservation and Development Commission&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2:30 p.m.&lt;strong&gt; Break&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2:45 p.m.&lt;strong&gt; Strategies for funding ecosystem restoration to mitigate climate change&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Sam Schuchat, CA State Coastal Conservancy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3:10 p.m.&lt;strong&gt; Panel Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;All participants&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;4:00 p.m.&lt;strong&gt; Conclusions and wrap up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Edwin Grosholz, University of California, Davis&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This seminar is free and open to the public&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/seminar/2015/05/07/sfbay/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/seminar/2015/05/07/sfbay/</guid>
        
        
        <category>seminar</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sustainability progress should precede seafood market access, researchers urge</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This article appeared in UCD Dateline on May 5, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demand for seafood from wild fisheries and aquaculture around the world has nearly doubled over the past four decades. In the past several years, major retailers in developed countries have committed to source their seafood from only sustainably certified fisheries and aquaculture, even though it is not clear where that supply will come from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A team of researchers led by the University of California, Davis, has focused its attention on fishery improvement projects, or FIPs, which are designed to bring seafood from wild fisheries to the certified market, with only a promise of sustainability in the future. They conclude that FIPs need to be fine tuned to ensure that fisheries are delivering on their promises. The researchers’ policy forum titled “Secure Sustainable Seafood from Developing Countries” will be published May 1 in the journal Science. The related abstract and podcast are available online at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/348/6234/504.summary&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/348/6234/504.summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re cautiously optimistic that fishery improvement projects, which fast-track access to international markets, can lead to sustainable fisheries, especially in developing countries,” said UC Davis Professor James Sanchirico, associate director of the UC Davis Coastal and Marine Sciences Institute. Encouraging sustainable seafood Retailers like Walmart in the U.S. and Sainsbury’s in the U.K. have promised that soon all the fresh, frozen, farmed and wild seafood they sell will come from sustainable sources. Respected, private third-party certifying programs like the Marine Stewardship Council are helping to ensure compliance with meaningful sustainability standards designed to help conserve fish populations and protect oceans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While many of the sustainability standards have been met by commercial fisheries in the developed world, fisheries overseen by developing countries make up only 7 percent of MSC-certified fisheries, even though these developing-country fisheries account for about half of all seafood entering the international market.
Fishery improvement projects aim to get fisheries on a path to sustainability and potentially certification by the MSC. These projects involve partnerships between the fishermen and firms up and down the international seafood supply chain. A critical objective of the partnerships is to create market incentives for improvements by allowing seafood from these developing-country fisheries to enter the potentially more lucrative export market for certified seafood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is hoped that the projects will protect marine life and ecosystems in areas where local and national governments have not acted to oversee sustainable practices, while also satisfying the demand for sustainable seafood,” said Gabriel Sampson, UC Davis graduate student and lead author of the study. Potential ‘race to the bottom’ in standards Sampson and colleagues report that seafood from two-thirds of developing-world fisheries enrolled in fishery improvement projects is already being bought by retailers, intending to satisfy their sustainability commitments while making little progress in improving their management. Fishery management reforms should include data collection and ongoing monitoring, strengthening harvest and access rights to the resources, limits on the catch, and instituting traceability throughout the supply chain, the researchers say. If access to the fisheries is not better regulated, the current efforts by retailers to secure sustainable, wild-caught seafood could stimulate a “race to fish” and ultimately undermine the sustainability claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without the proper safeguards to ensure progress and reforms in fishery improvement projects, fisheries with full sustainability certification could find their market benefits diluted by the increased competition for a share of the global certified seafood market. Having multiple types of certified seafood in the market could lead to a “race to the bottom” in sustainability standards, unless the fishery improvement projects are carefully monitored to make sure that seafood retailers closely adhere to the sustainable-improvement requirements for market access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The retailers and organizations involved with managing fishery improvement projects need to insist on progress toward reforms from the fishery as a condition for purchasing seafood from that fishery,” Sanchirico said. “This would likely lead to more durable conservation and greater assurance for consumers that marketing claims of ‘sustainable’ seafood are valid,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;b&gt;Authors on the commentary were...&lt;/b&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gabriel Sampson, James N. Sanchirico, and J. Edward Taylor  of UC Davis&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cathy A. Roheim of the University of Idaho, Moscow&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Simon R. Bush of Wageningen University in the Netherlands&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Edward H. Allison of the University of Washington, Seattle&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;James L. Anderson of the University of Florida, Gainesville&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Natalie C. Ban of the University of Victoria in Canada&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rod Fujita of the Environmental Defense Fund&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stacy Jupiter of the Wildlife Conservation Society&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jono R. Wilson of The Nature Conservancy&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Media contact(s):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;b&gt;Jim Sanchirico&lt;/b&gt;, Environmental Science and Policy, (530) 754-9883, jsanchirico@ucdavis.edu &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Simon Bush&lt;/b&gt;, Wageningen University, the Netherlands, 0317-483310, simon.bush@wur.nl &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;J. Edward Taylor&lt;/b&gt;, Agricultural and Resource Economics, (530) 564-0443, jetaylor@ucdavis.edu&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pat Bailey&lt;/b&gt;, UC Davis News Service, (530) 752-9843, pjbailey@ucdavis.edu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 15:11:38 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2015/05/06/Sustainability-progress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2015/05/06/Sustainability-progress/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CABA announces scholarship winners for 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
	CABA would like to offer it&#39;s congratulations to this years scholarship winners. These scholarships would not be possible without the generous donations and support for fisheries research at U.C. Davis by the following organizations...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;California Fly Fishers Unlimited,&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;California Fly Fishers Unlimited (CFFU)&quot; src=&quot;/media//news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen,&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen (DVFF)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Marin Rod and Gun Club,&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Marin Rod and Gun Club (MRGC)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fly Fishers of Davis,&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Fly Fishers of Davis&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This years scholarship winners and their abstracts are as follows...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Meredith Nagel was awarded the Bob Bittner scholarship, $3000.00, from California Fly Fishers Unlimited.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meredith is a PhD candidate in the Ecology Graduate Group. Her adviser is Dr. Swee Teh from the department of Veterinary Medicine (Anatomy, Physiology and Cell Biology) The focus of this laboratory is
the Aquatic Heath Program (AHP) which strives to promote and protect the well-being of all aquatic species and their environments by investigating the behavioral, anatomical, and physiological components of individual organisms and applying them to the ecosystem scale. Prior to coming to U.C. Davis, Meredith earned a Bachelor of Science degree in environmental studies, emphasis in marine ecology from U.C. Santa Barbara. She also has earned a Master’s of Science degree from the University of Auckland, New Zealand in Population Genetics and Molecular Ecology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Her abstract…
	&lt;i&gt;My proposed research includes investigating the effects of temperature and food-availability on the growth and survival of delta smelt (Hypomesus transpacificus). While there are many potential causes for the decline in delta smelt population abundances, my research focuses on changes in the Bay-Delta food web ecology and environmental parameters as potential stressors and cause for low survival of the species. The overarching goal of this research is to provide laboratory-tested data to conservation managers to aid in the restoration of the Bay-Delta food webs and ecosystem health. The funds from this scholarship will help with the cost of running the experiment at CABA.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Denise De Carion was awarded the Bob Wise Carver Scholarship, $2500.00,  from The Diablo Valley Fly Fisherman.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She currently is a PhD student in the Ecology Graduate Group with an emphasis on conservation ecology. She works in the laboratory of Peter Moyle in the department of Wildlife and Fisheries Conservation Biology. The purpose of this laboratory is the study and conservation of California’s native fish species. Here she collaborates with researchers from the U.C. Davis Suisun Marsh Fish Study. Denise has also earned a Bachelor of Science in Environmental Science from U.C. Davis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her abstract…
&lt;i&gt;The purpose of my research is to advance our knowledge and understanding of how tidal marshes in the San Francisco Estuary provide food for commercially and recreationally significant species such as Chinook salmon and striped bass, which rely on estuaries during early life stages. My approach is intended to provide a broad perspective on how fishes feed in tidal marshes and then transfer energy and nutrients to the rest of the estuary. The estuarine ecosystem is experiencing major declines among many estuarine-dependent species, and these declines are probably a symptom of a much greater problem: food availability.&lt;/i&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Myfanwy Johnson was awarded  a scholarship, $1850.00, from the Marin Rod and Gun Club.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She currently is pursuing a PhD in animal behavior in the bio-telemetry laboratory of Dr. Peter Klimley in the department of Wildlife and Fisheries Conservation Biology at U.C. Davis.  The mission of this laboratory is the utilization of state-of-art tracking technologies with geographic information systems to understand fundamental physiological, behavioral, and ecological processes.  Our studies aim to elucidate the link between an animal&#39;s behavior and its social and physical environment.Prior to coming to U.C. Davis, Myfanwy received a B.A. in Marine Science and a B.S. in Conservation and Resource Studies, both from U.C. Berkeley in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Her Abstract...&lt;i&gt;The goal of my research is to describe the differences in movement behavior between two species of native migratory fish (white sturgeon and Chinook salmon).  Both species are not only ecologically important to the Central Valley, but also belong to culturally- and economically-important recreational fisheries.  In order to assure that these fish will be here for future generations of sportsmen  and women to enjoy, it is critical that management actions reconcile the ecological success of the species with the demands of human stakeholders co-existing in the Central Valley.  A key part of achieving successful reconciliation  practices is understanding  how these fish are navigating their migratory  landscape, as well as the factors affecting  their migratory success.  My project uses acoustic telemetry to illuminate the movement patterns of salmon and white sturgeon in the Yolo Bypass, and to examine the environmental cues they may be responding to. I hope to provide managers with reliable guidelines for implementing reconcilatory management measures.  A CABA scholarship will help by providing the funds necessary to purchase field equipment and to analyze tissue samples from tagged fish, both of which are vital to the success of my research.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Patrick Grof-Tiza received a scholarship,1850.00, from the Marin Rod and Gun Club.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patrick is a PhD candidate in the Ecology graduate group. He is co-advised by Dr. Rick Karban and Dr. Marcel Holyoak in the departments of Entomology and Environmental Science and Policy respectively. Patrick also has earned a Master of Science degree in Ecology from U.C. Davis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
His abstract…&lt;i&gt;Dragonflies and damselflies (collectively odontes) are important food resources for fish in many aquatic systems. My research will investigate how physical defenses of riparian plants can facilitate molting odonates and increase their likelihood of survival. Maintaining high populations of aquatic insects including odonates can improve fish health and increase reproductive output. The CABA scholarship will allow me to purchase materials to test my hypothesis. This work could potentially lead to a strategy to increase the abundance and quality of food resources for fish and inform riparian restoration efforts.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grace Ha was awarded a scholarship, $1500.00, from the Fly Fishers of Davis.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Grace is a PhD candidate in the Ecology Graduate group here at U.C. Davis. She is advised by Dr. Susan Williams in the department of Evolution and Ecology and is associated with the Bodega Marine Laboratory. The focus of the laboratory is the study of seagrass, algae and coral reek systems in the near shore. Prior to coming to U.C. Davis, Grace earned a Bachelor of Science in biology from Cornell University in 2010. Grace was also a Fulbright Scholar in South Korea studying the ecological knowledge of traditional diving women (haenyeo).   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Her abstract…&lt;i&gt;I study how prey species use color to camouflage in eelgrass, and how the visual abilities of surfperch predators shape those adaptations. This is important because eelgrass is recognized as a nursery habitat for species such as salmon, rockfish, herring, and surfperch, but we do not fully understand how this is. Focusing on color as an element of habitat structure, I am studying an aspect of eelgrass ecology that is related to water clarity and nutrient concentrations through the underwater light environment. Given the effect of pollution and terrestrial runoff on these environmental factors, my research is directly relevant and beneficial to sport and commercial fisheries because it could inform how these issues affect eelgrass food webs and the fish they support.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 14:49:03 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2015/04/22/CABA-announces-scholarship-winners-2015/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2015/04/22/CABA-announces-scholarship-winners-2015/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CABA announces scholarships for 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Open to U.C. Davis graduate and undergraduate* students working on Fisheries Biology and/or Riparian or Limnetic Ecology benefiting California&#39;s recreational fisheries.  Funds are awarded directly to the student and may be used for any research-related purpose, including supplies, travel, equipment, salary support, fees, etc.  For additional information and application package click here &lt;a href=&quot;/media/news/2015_caba_scholarship_application.doc&quot;&gt;2015 Scholarship Application&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please email applications to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jlboulanger@ucdavis.edu&quot;&gt;Joyce Boulanger&lt;/a&gt;, jlboulanger@ucdavis.edu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All applications must be submitted by Friday, January 30, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Only the Bob Bittner Scholarship is open to both graduate and undergraduate students in good standing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clubs’ scholarship committees are looking for proposals which have clear relevance to sport fishing in California. Click here for previous years winning abstracts...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
This years scholarships are sponsored by the following sports fishing groups...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img alt=&quot;Marin Rod and Gun Club (MRGC)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Marin Rod and Gun Club&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt; is offering two scholarships of &lt;b&gt;$1500.00 each.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img alt=&quot;California Fly Fishers Unlimited (CFFU)&quot; src=&quot;/media//news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;California Fly Fishers Unlimited&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt; are offering the Bob Bittner Scholarship of &lt;b&gt;$2500.00.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img alt=&quot;Fly Fishers of Davis&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Fly Fishers of Davis&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt; are offering a scholarship of &lt;b&gt;$1500.00.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img alt=&quot;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen (DVFF)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt; are offering the Bob Wisecarver Scholarship of &lt;b&gt;$2500.00.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 18:40:45 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2015/04/21/CABA-announces-scholarship-for-2015/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2015/04/21/CABA-announces-scholarship-for-2015/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sturgeon in the Sacramento - San Joaquin Watershed.  New insights to support conservation and management.</title>
        <description>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image-inline captioned image-inline&quot; src=&quot;/media/sturgeon1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wild White Sturgeon&quot; height=&quot;128&quot; width=&quot;318&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image-inline captioned image-inline&quot; src=&quot;/media/sturgeon2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Delta sturgeon&quot; height=&quot;266&quot; width=&quot;368&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image-inline captioned image-inline&quot; src=&quot;/media/sturgeon3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wild Green Sturgeon&quot; height=&quot;124&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Delta Science Program&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Center for Aquatic Biology and Aquaculture&lt;/strong&gt; are pleased to announce a seminar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video of this seminar is now available at the following link...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://ats.ucdavis.edu/ats-video/?kpid=0_a1ddomr5&quot;&gt;http://ats.ucdavis.edu/ats-video/?kpid=0_a1ddomr5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Green and White Sturgeon, two distinct species with disparate life histories, reside in the Sacramento/San Joaquin Watershed and pose different challenges related to conservation and management . Green Sturgeon, a more marine species, migrates in spring to spawn in the headwaters of the Sacramento River before returning to the estuary during the fall. After their eggs hatch, the larvae are transported downstream with juveniles rearing within the Delta and San Francisco Bay. Adults migrate out the Golden Gate and travel northward along the continental shelf to the waters off Washington and Canada. By contrast, White Sturgeon appears to spawn exclusively in the lower Sacramento River watershed and remain within the San Francisco Estuary throughout their lifespan. &lt;br /&gt;These coarse and contrasting life history descriptions provide the context for this day-long symposium that will present new information about biology and natural history of these two species. Considerable research has been undertaken to understand the physiology, behavior, and ecology of these species. The goal of this symposium is to shed light on current unknowns, some of which are currently being addressed by new electronic tracking technologies and physiological techniques, and to help guide enhanced management and conservation efforts within the Sacramento/San Joaquin watershed. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Tentative Agenda&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9:00 – 9:10&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome and Introduction &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Dr.Rainer Hoenicke,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Depty Executive Officer Delta Science Program&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9:10-9:35 - An introduction to green and white sturgeon in the Sacramento/San Joaquin Watershed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  A. Peter Klimley, Adjunct Professor. – University of California, Davis&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9:35-10:00 - Long-term trends in the size of the green and white sturgeon populations determined from historical fish surveys – Are either species populations declining?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Marty Gingras, Fisheries Biologist – California Department of Fish and Wildlife&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10:00-10:25 - &lt;em&gt;Physiological and Behavioral Studies of Sturgeonin the Sacramento-San Joaquin Watershed- Implicationsfor Conservation and Future Studies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Joseph Cech, Emeritus Professor, and Nann Fangue, Assistant Professor – &lt;/em&gt;Uni. of Calif, Davis&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 10:25-10:45 – Break&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10:45-11:10 -&lt;em&gt; Timing of Green and White Sturgeon Movements in the San FranciscoBat, Delta and Sacramento River&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Emily Miller, Ph.D. Candidate – University of California, Davis&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11:10-11:35 - The Size and Spatial Distribution of SDPS Adult Green Sturgeon in the Sacramento River Compared to the Klamath and Rogue Rivers -- an Aggregated Species Vulnerable to Exploitation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Ethan Mora, Ph.D. Candidate -- University of California, Davis&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11:35-12:00 - An Overview of What We Think We Know About Green Sturgeon and White Sturgeon in the Feather River  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alicia Seesholtz, Fisheries Biologist – California Department of Water Resources&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 12:00 - 1:10 – Lunch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1:10-1:35 - White Sturgon in the San Joaquin River-When,Why,and What We Are Going To Do About It?  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zachery Jackson, Fisheries Biologist – United State Dept. of Fish and Wildlife&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1:35-2:00&lt;em&gt; Those Crazy Jumping Suwannee River Sturgeons-What&#39;s It All About?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Kenneth Sulak, Fisheries Biologist US Geological Survey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2:00-2:25 - Integrating Sensory Ecology and Behavior with the Management of Juvenile Green Sturgeon (Acipenser medirostris).&quot; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Jamilynn Poletto, Ph.D. – Postdoctoral Researcher – University of California, Davis&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 2:25 – 2:50 – Break&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2:50-3:15 - Is Recovery of Green Sturgeon Possible? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt; David Woodbury, Green Sturgeon Recovery Coordinator, National Marine Fisheries Service&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3:15-3:40 - Empirical and Modeling Studies of Spawning Habitat Preferencees in Green Sturgeon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Megan Wyman&lt;/strong&gt;, Postdoctoral Researcher, UC Davis (on behalf of&lt;strong&gt; Michael Thomas&lt;/strong&gt; Staff Researcher UC Davis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt; 3:40-5:00-Panel Discussion: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Biological and Physical Information Do We Need to Best Manage and Conserve Green and White Sturgeon Populations in the Sacramento/San Joaquin River Watershed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Panelists: Joseph Cech (UCD), Nann Fangue (UCD), Marty Gingras (CDFW), Zachery Jackson (USFW), Emily Miller (UCD), Ethan Mora (UCD), Jamilynn Poletto (UCD), Andrea Schreier (UCD), Alicia Seesholtz (CDWR), Kenneth Sulak (USGS), David Woodbury (NMFS)&lt;strong&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;Megan Wyman&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;(UCD)&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, Moderator: Pete Klimley (UCD)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5:00 -&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Closing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; A. Peter Klimley &lt;/strong&gt;Adjunct Professor, UC Davis&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This seminar is free and open to the public.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/seminar/2015/03/03/sturgeon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/seminar/2015/03/03/sturgeon/</guid>
        
        
        <category>seminar</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meeting Nature Halfway on a Floodway</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;PROGRAM &lt;br /&gt;A grand experiment in species conservation is underway on the Yolo Bypass, a farmed floodway of the Sacramento River. Rather than restore the engineered floodplain to some natural state, researchers are exploring possibilities of a re-­‐engineered human-­‐dominated landscape that allows native species to coexist. Engineers, ecologists and economists discuss how habitat for fish and fowl might be reconciled with floods and farming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Video of this seminar is now available online at...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://webcast.ucdavis.edu/llnd/d4fc6e4&quot;&gt; http://webcast.ucdavis.edu/llnd/d4fc6e4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 -­‐ 9:10 Opening Remarks. Peter Goodwin, Delta Science Program &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;9:10 -­‐ 9:20    Overview of Management and Habitat on the Yolo Bypass &lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Jay Lund, UC Davis Center for Watershed Sciences &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;9:20 -­‐ 10 The Accidental Model: the Yolo Bypass and the Multiple Benefits of Floodplain Reconnection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Jeff Opperman, Great Rivers Partnership, The Nature Conservancy &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;10 -­‐ 10:25    Yolo Bypass Issues and Hopes. &lt;strong&gt;Petrea Marchand, Consero Solutions &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;10:25 -­‐10:45&lt;strong&gt; BREAK&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;10:45 -­‐ 11:10 Past, Present and Future Roles of the Yolo Bypass in Flood Management &lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Michael Mierzwa, California Department of Water Resources &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;11:10 -­‐ 11:35 Balancing Competing Interests: Insights From Hydraulic Modeling &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt; William A. Fleenor, UC Davis Center for Watershed Sciences&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;11:35 -­‐ 12 &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Integrated Management.&lt;strong&gt; Robyn Suddeth, CH2MHILL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;12 -­‐ 1:15 &lt;strong&gt;LUNCH&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1:15 -­‐ 1:40 Native Fishes and Managed Floodplains: Mimicking Natural Processes &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Ted Sommer, California Department of Water&lt;/strong&gt; Resources &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1:40 -­‐ 2:05 Yolo Bypass, Waterfowl and the Pacific Flyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Greg Yarris, Central Valley Joint Venture, U.S. Fish &amp;amp; Wildlife Service&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2:05 -­‐ 2:30 The Mercury Mêlée: Costs vs. Benefits of Methylmercury Controls in Delta Floodplains. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Stephen McCord, McCord Environmental&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2:30 -­‐ 2:45&lt;strong&gt; BREAK&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2:45 -­‐ 3:30      &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Panel Discussion: How Do We Reconcile Competing Interests on the Yolo Bypass? &lt;br /&gt; J&lt;strong&gt;ohn Brennan, Cal Marsh &amp;amp; Farm Ventures; Cindy Tuttle, Yolo County; &lt;br /&gt; Robin Kulakow, Yolo Basin Foundation; Jeremy Arrich, California Dept. of Water Resources Kris Tjernell, California Natural Resources  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3:30 Closing Remarks. &lt;strong&gt;Jay Lund, UC Davis Center for Watershed Sciences &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/seminar/2014/12/09/Meeting-nature/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/seminar/2014/12/09/Meeting-nature/</guid>
        
        
        <category>seminar</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title> Emerging Techniques to Quantify the Effects of Environmental Change in Bay-Delta Organisms</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image-left captioned&quot; src=&quot;/media/emerging_techniques.png&quot; alt=&quot;BA Emerg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Delta Science Program and the UC Davis Center for Aquatic Biology and Aquaculture (CABA) are pleased to present a Science Synthesis Seminar.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://webcast.ucdavis.edu/llnd/60bab152&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://webcast.ucdavis.edu/llnd/60bab152&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web cast of this seminar can be found here... &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://webcast.ucdavis.edu/llnd/60bab152&quot;&gt;http://webcast.ucdavis.edu/llnd/60bab152&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://webcast.ucdavis.edu/llnd/60bab152&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OVERVIEW:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The San Francisco Bay Delta system represents one of the most ecologically and economically diverse and important ecosystems in the world. It has been the focus of significant research and monitoring efforts for a long time and represents a well-studied system with many activities taking place to preserve its ecological health while maximizing its economic value. This symposium will present novel high-throughput analytical approaches, technologies, and workflows that support broader and more in-depth characterization of environmental conditions on Bay-Delta organisms than previously possible. In particular, modern approaches for high-throughput molecular phenotyping (e.g. proteomics), population genomics, and physiological phenotyping will be presented. In addition, the seminar will explore how these approaches can be linked to and integrated with ongoing high-throughput environmental monitoring programs and biological surveys of Bay-Delta organisms. A panel discussion will explore ways of finding better linkages in this regard and inform participants about needs and opportunities for leveraging the full potential of modern high-throughput analytical technologies. Such integration will enable us to much more comprehensively assess how specific changes in the environment affect Bay-Delta organisms and inform sustainable management practices.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Program: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9:00 - 9:15 - Welcome and
Introduction - Dr. Peter Goodwin Lead Scientist Delta Science Program &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;and Dr. Dietmar Kueltz – UC
Davis Animal Science&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9:15 – 9:35 - The state of
aquatic organisms in the SF Bay Delta ecosystem: an overview &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Dr. Peter Moyle - UC Davis&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://wfcb.ucdavis.edu/www/Faculty/Peter/petermoyle/Introduction.html&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://wfcb.ucdavis.edu/www/Faculty/Peter/petermoyle/Introduction.html&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; http://wfcb.ucdavis.edu/www/Faculty/Peter/petermoyle/Introduction.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://wfcb.ucdavis.edu/www/Faculty/Peter/petermoyle/Introduction.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9:35 – 10:15 - Existing fish
survey and monitoring programs – What are we looking for, how and why? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Dr. Ted Sommer - California
Department of Water Resources&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.water.ca.gov/aes/staff/sommer.cfm&quot;&gt;http://www.water.ca.gov/aes/staff/sommer.cfm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 10:15 – 10:35 - Break &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10:55 – 11:15 - Continuous
biogeochemical data – Developing the baseline to support existing and emerging&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; biological assessments &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Dr. Brian Bergamaschi - US
Geological Survey &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://profile.usgs.gov/bbergama&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; http://profile.usgs.gov/bbergama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11:15 – 11:55 - Modern
ecophysiological approaches to studying the biological state of SF Bay Delta
organisms &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Dr. Nann Fangue - UC Davis &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://fanguelab.ucdavis.edu/&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; http://fanguelab.ucdavis.edu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 11:55 – 1:10 - Lunch break &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1:10 – 1:45 - Integrating
data rich techniques in process based models – Green Sturgeon &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Dr. Pedro Vaz - UC Davis Animal Science&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1:45 - 2:25 Real-time management of fishes in the watershed with acoustic array.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dr. Peter Klimley - UC Davis&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://wfcb.ucdavis.edu/www/faculty/Pete/index.asp&quot;&gt;http://wfcb.ucdavis.edu/www/faculty/Pete/index.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2:25 – 3:05 -
High-throughput proteomics approaches for assessing environmental impacts on SF
Bay Delta organisms &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Dr. Dietmar Kueltz - UC
Davis &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://kueltzlab.ucdavis.edu/&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; http://kueltzlab.ucdavis.edu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 3:05 - 3:20 - Break &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3:20 – 4:00 – Genomics
approaches to studying SF Bay Delta organisms &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Dr. Mike Miller - UC Davis&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/millermichaelryan/&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/millermichaelryan/&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; https://sites.google.com/site/millermichaelryan/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;4:00 – 4:50 - Panel
Discussion: &lt;/strong&gt;Opportunities and Barriers – How to leverage and integrate emerging environmental monitoring techniques with existing monitoring programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panelists: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Matt Nobriga (USFWS), Ted Sommer (CA DWR), Steve
Slater (CA DFW), Swee Teh (UCD), Jim Hobbs (UC Davis), Dietmar Kueltz (UC
Davis), Nann Fangue (UC Davis), Mike Miller (UC Davis)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4:50 – 5:00 - Closing
Remarks - &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dietmar Kueltz - UC Davis Animal Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; This is a free public event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more information contact – Garrett Liles –Delta Science Program garrett.liles@deltacouncil.ca.gov – (916) 445-5694&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/seminar/2014/05/12/emerging-techniques/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/seminar/2014/05/12/emerging-techniques/</guid>
        
        
        <category>seminar</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lower Food Web Dynamics in California&#39;s Bay-Delta EcoSystem:</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
	Seminar Objective – Broad decadal declines of lower pelagic fish populations in California’s Bay-Delta ecosystem, with concomitant declines in primary and secondary productivity, have driven policy, management, and regulatory efforts to identify approaches that will restore the pelagic food web. The science and management community working in this system are poised to embark on planning and restoration activities that will encompass large portions of this diverse landscape, yet evidence directly linking shallow aquatic habitat restoration and pelagic food webs remains uncertain. This symposium will characterize the major components and factors affecting the lower pelagic food web - e.g. nutrient supplies, phytoplankton production, flow/transport/flux, benthic grazing – and explore potential interaction/feedback between these factors and proposed restoration and management activities in the Delta. These dynamic and interconnected factors must be considered through an interdisciplinary perspective to identify the best path forward. This event will provide a forum to synthesize knowledge and lessons learned, both in California’s and other estuarine systems around the world, and stimulate discussion to identify research and management actions that will support effective restoration activities and promote resilient aquatic ecosystems.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image-right captioned&quot; src=&quot;/media/lower_web.png&quot; alt=&quot;BayDelta EcoSystem&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guest speakers will include: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sami Souissi, University of Lille, France&lt;br /&gt;Mark Brush, Virginia Institute of Marine Sciences&lt;br /&gt;Wim Kimmerer Romberg Tiburon Center&lt;br /&gt;Lisa Lucas, USGS&lt;br /&gt;Alex Parker, California Maritime Academy&lt;br /&gt;Jan Thompson, USGS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow link below for video of seminar...&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://webcast.ucdavis.edu/llnd/4a120027&quot;&gt;http://webcast.ucdavis.edu/llnd/4a120027&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda – &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, February 18 2014 UC Davis ARC Ballroom&lt;br /&gt; 8:30 - Welcome and Opening Remarks&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;em&gt;Dr. Peter Goodwin, Lead Scientist Delta Science Program &amp;amp;&lt;br /&gt; Dr. Brian Bergamaschi, United States Geological Survey&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 8:45 - Keynote Speaker&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;Zooplankton and Estuary food web dynamics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Dr. Sami Souissi&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://log.univ-littoral.fr/Souissi&quot;&gt;http://log.univ-littoral.fr/Souissi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 9:35 - Causes, consequences, and potential remedies to low food web productivity in brackish waters of the San Francisco Estuary&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt; Dr. Wim Kimmerer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://http://rtc.sfsu.edu/research/in_kimmerer.html&quot;&gt;http://http://rtc.sfsu.edu/research/in_kimmerer.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 10:25- 10:40 Break&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10:40 – The Physical Environment and Dynamics&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt; Dr. Lisa Lucas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://http://sfbay.wr.usgs.gov/access/wqdata/overview/people/lisa.html&quot;&gt;http://http://sfbay.wr.usgs.gov/access/wqdata/overview/people/lisa.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Default&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11:30 – Nutrient Dynamics/Modeling &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dr. Mark Brush&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.vims.edu/people/brush_mj/index.phphttp://&quot;&gt;http://www.vims.edu/people/brush_mj/index.phphttp://&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;        &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;     12:20 -1:30 – Lunch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1:30 – Nutrients – Conflicting Dynamics –&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt; Dr. Alex Parker&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.csum.edu/web/academics/faculty3http://&quot;&gt;http://www.csum.edu/web/academics/faculty3http://&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2:20 - Benthic Impacts- Clam Grazing&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt; Dr. Jan Thompson&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://profile.usgs.gov/professional/mypage.php?rfs=y&amp;amp;name=jthompsohttp://&quot;&gt;http://profile.usgs.gov/professional/mypage.php?rfs=y&amp;amp;name=jthompsohttp://&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;    3:10 – 3:30 Break&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3:30 – Synthesis Panel Discussion&lt;/strong&gt; – (combining speakers and *restoration ecology panelists), this group will discuss how local and landscape scale restoration may shape future aquatic ecosystem resilience. The general focus will concern the future and what the research, management and implementation community will need to know/find out to develop a more resilient landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4:30- Final Thoughts&lt;/strong&gt; –&lt;em&gt; Dr. Brian Bergamaschi &lt;/em&gt;(USGS)
    &lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;* Restoration Ecology Panel –&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;This group will probe the linkages between wetland restoration activities and aquatic food webs in a question-and-answer format with the primary speakers.
    &lt;br /&gt;Panel members include:
    &lt;br /&gt; Carl Wilcox – California Department of Fish and Wildlife
    &lt;br /&gt; Stuart Siegel – Wetlands and Water Resources, Inc.
    &lt;br /&gt; Kathy Boyer – San Francisco State University - Romberg Tiburon Center
    &lt;br /&gt; Swee Teh – UC Davis
    &lt;br /&gt; Erwin Van Nieuwenhuyse – United States Bureau of Reclamation
    &lt;br /&gt; Larry Brown – United States Geological Survey
    &lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For more information contact- Garrett Liles - Delta Science Program &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;garrett.liles@deltacouncil.ca.gov&lt;strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; (916)445-5694&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The seminar is FREE and OPEN TO THE PUBLIC.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/seminar/2014/02/18/lower-web/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/seminar/2014/02/18/lower-web/</guid>
        
        
        <category>seminar</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2014 Scholarships Available EXTENDED DEADLINE for turning in scholarship applications Tuesday February 18 , 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
Open to U.C. Davis graduate and undergraduate* students working on &lt;b&gt;Fisheries Biology&lt;/b&gt; and/or &lt;b&gt;Riparian&lt;/b&gt; or &lt;b&gt;Limnetic Ecology benefiting California&#39;s recreational fisheries&lt;/b&gt;.  Funds are awarded directly to the student and may be used for any research-related purpose, including supplies, travel, equipment, salary support, fees, etc.  For additional information and application package click &lt;a href=&quot;/media/news/2014_caba_scholarship_app.docx&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; Please email applications to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:vewhitworth@ucdavis.edu&quot;&gt;Victoria Whitworth&lt;/a&gt;, vewhitworth@ucdavis.edu.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All applications must be submitted by Tuesday, February 18, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;* Only the Bob Bittner Scholarship is open to both graduate and undergraduate students in good standing.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clubs’ scholarship committees are looking for proposals which have clear relevance to sport fishing in California. Click &lt;a href=&quot;/news/2012/04/18/Abstracts-of-the-2012-Scholarship-Winners&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for previous years winning abstracts...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
This years scholarships are sponsored by the following sports fishing groups...&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen (DVFF)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Bob Wisecarver Scholarship, Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen&lt;/b&gt;,&lt;i&gt;one grant of $2500.00.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Marin Rod and Gun Club (MRGC)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Marin Rod and Gun Club Scholarships&lt;/b&gt;,&lt;i&gt;two grants of $1500.00 each.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;California Fly Fishers Unlimited (CFFU)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Bob Bittner Scholarship, California Fly Fishers Unlimited&lt;/b&gt;,&lt;i&gt;one grant of $2600.00.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Fly Fishers of Davis&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fly Fishers of Davis&lt;/b&gt;,&lt;i&gt;one scholarship of &lt;b&gt;$1500.00.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 10:25:59 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2014/02/13/2014-scholarships-available-extended-deadline-2014/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2014/02/13/2014-scholarships-available-extended-deadline-2014/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
