<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Center for Aquatic Biology and Aquaculture</title>
    <description>The Center for Aquatic Biology and Aquaculture (CABA) was established to provide leadership, focus, and support to University of California Davis researchers in addressing problems associated with California’s cultured and wild aquatic biological resources.
</description>
    <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://caba.ucdavis.edu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 13:56:26 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 13:56:26 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>CABA Scholarships for 2016 are available</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
Open to all UC Davis graduate students who are working on Fisheries Biology and/or Riparian or Limnetic Ecology research benefiting California&#39;s recreational fisheries. The CFFU scholarship is also open to junior and senior undergraduate students. Funds are awarded directly to the student and may be used for any research-related purpose, including supplies, travel, equipment, salary support, fees, etc.
For additional information and application package click &lt;a href=&quot;media/news/caba_scholarship_application_2016.doc&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Applications are due January 29 2016.
Please email completed applications to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jlboulanger@ucdavis.edu&quot;&gt;Joyce L Boulanger&lt;/a&gt; at jlboulanger@ucdavis.edu
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This year&#39;s available scholarships are:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;California Fly Fishers Unlimited (CFFU)&quot; src=&quot;/media//news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;California Fly Fishers Unlimited (CFFU), Bob Bittner Scholarship One $2,500 Scholarship&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen (DVFF)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen (DVFF), Bob Wisecarver Scholarship One $2,500 Scholarship &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Fly Fishers of Davis (FFD)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fly Fishers of Davis (FFD) Scholarship One $1,500 Scholarship&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Marin Rod and Gun Club (MRGC)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marin Rod and Gun Club (MRGC) Scholarships Two $2,000 Scholarships&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 15:58:42 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2016/01/07/CABA-Scholarships-for-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2016/01/07/CABA-Scholarships-for-2016/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sustainability progress should precede seafood market access, researchers urge</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This article appeared in UCD Dateline on May 5, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demand for seafood from wild fisheries and aquaculture around the world has nearly doubled over the past four decades. In the past several years, major retailers in developed countries have committed to source their seafood from only sustainably certified fisheries and aquaculture, even though it is not clear where that supply will come from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A team of researchers led by the University of California, Davis, has focused its attention on fishery improvement projects, or FIPs, which are designed to bring seafood from wild fisheries to the certified market, with only a promise of sustainability in the future. They conclude that FIPs need to be fine tuned to ensure that fisheries are delivering on their promises. The researchers’ policy forum titled “Secure Sustainable Seafood from Developing Countries” will be published May 1 in the journal Science. The related abstract and podcast are available online at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/348/6234/504.summary&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/348/6234/504.summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re cautiously optimistic that fishery improvement projects, which fast-track access to international markets, can lead to sustainable fisheries, especially in developing countries,” said UC Davis Professor James Sanchirico, associate director of the UC Davis Coastal and Marine Sciences Institute. Encouraging sustainable seafood Retailers like Walmart in the U.S. and Sainsbury’s in the U.K. have promised that soon all the fresh, frozen, farmed and wild seafood they sell will come from sustainable sources. Respected, private third-party certifying programs like the Marine Stewardship Council are helping to ensure compliance with meaningful sustainability standards designed to help conserve fish populations and protect oceans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While many of the sustainability standards have been met by commercial fisheries in the developed world, fisheries overseen by developing countries make up only 7 percent of MSC-certified fisheries, even though these developing-country fisheries account for about half of all seafood entering the international market.
Fishery improvement projects aim to get fisheries on a path to sustainability and potentially certification by the MSC. These projects involve partnerships between the fishermen and firms up and down the international seafood supply chain. A critical objective of the partnerships is to create market incentives for improvements by allowing seafood from these developing-country fisheries to enter the potentially more lucrative export market for certified seafood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is hoped that the projects will protect marine life and ecosystems in areas where local and national governments have not acted to oversee sustainable practices, while also satisfying the demand for sustainable seafood,” said Gabriel Sampson, UC Davis graduate student and lead author of the study. Potential ‘race to the bottom’ in standards Sampson and colleagues report that seafood from two-thirds of developing-world fisheries enrolled in fishery improvement projects is already being bought by retailers, intending to satisfy their sustainability commitments while making little progress in improving their management. Fishery management reforms should include data collection and ongoing monitoring, strengthening harvest and access rights to the resources, limits on the catch, and instituting traceability throughout the supply chain, the researchers say. If access to the fisheries is not better regulated, the current efforts by retailers to secure sustainable, wild-caught seafood could stimulate a “race to fish” and ultimately undermine the sustainability claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without the proper safeguards to ensure progress and reforms in fishery improvement projects, fisheries with full sustainability certification could find their market benefits diluted by the increased competition for a share of the global certified seafood market. Having multiple types of certified seafood in the market could lead to a “race to the bottom” in sustainability standards, unless the fishery improvement projects are carefully monitored to make sure that seafood retailers closely adhere to the sustainable-improvement requirements for market access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The retailers and organizations involved with managing fishery improvement projects need to insist on progress toward reforms from the fishery as a condition for purchasing seafood from that fishery,” Sanchirico said. “This would likely lead to more durable conservation and greater assurance for consumers that marketing claims of ‘sustainable’ seafood are valid,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;b&gt;Authors on the commentary were...&lt;/b&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gabriel Sampson, James N. Sanchirico, and J. Edward Taylor  of UC Davis&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cathy A. Roheim of the University of Idaho, Moscow&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Simon R. Bush of Wageningen University in the Netherlands&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Edward H. Allison of the University of Washington, Seattle&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;James L. Anderson of the University of Florida, Gainesville&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Natalie C. Ban of the University of Victoria in Canada&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rod Fujita of the Environmental Defense Fund&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stacy Jupiter of the Wildlife Conservation Society&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jono R. Wilson of The Nature Conservancy&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Media contact(s):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;b&gt;Jim Sanchirico&lt;/b&gt;, Environmental Science and Policy, (530) 754-9883, jsanchirico@ucdavis.edu &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Simon Bush&lt;/b&gt;, Wageningen University, the Netherlands, 0317-483310, simon.bush@wur.nl &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;J. Edward Taylor&lt;/b&gt;, Agricultural and Resource Economics, (530) 564-0443, jetaylor@ucdavis.edu&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pat Bailey&lt;/b&gt;, UC Davis News Service, (530) 752-9843, pjbailey@ucdavis.edu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 15:11:38 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2015/05/06/Sustainability-progress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2015/05/06/Sustainability-progress/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CABA announces scholarship winners for 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
	CABA would like to offer it&#39;s congratulations to this years scholarship winners. These scholarships would not be possible without the generous donations and support for fisheries research at U.C. Davis by the following organizations...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;California Fly Fishers Unlimited,&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;California Fly Fishers Unlimited (CFFU)&quot; src=&quot;/media//news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen,&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen (DVFF)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Marin Rod and Gun Club,&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Marin Rod and Gun Club (MRGC)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fly Fishers of Davis,&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Fly Fishers of Davis&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This years scholarship winners and their abstracts are as follows...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Meredith Nagel was awarded the Bob Bittner scholarship, $3000.00, from California Fly Fishers Unlimited.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meredith is a PhD candidate in the Ecology Graduate Group. Her adviser is Dr. Swee Teh from the department of Veterinary Medicine (Anatomy, Physiology and Cell Biology) The focus of this laboratory is
the Aquatic Heath Program (AHP) which strives to promote and protect the well-being of all aquatic species and their environments by investigating the behavioral, anatomical, and physiological components of individual organisms and applying them to the ecosystem scale. Prior to coming to U.C. Davis, Meredith earned a Bachelor of Science degree in environmental studies, emphasis in marine ecology from U.C. Santa Barbara. She also has earned a Master’s of Science degree from the University of Auckland, New Zealand in Population Genetics and Molecular Ecology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Her abstract…
	&lt;i&gt;My proposed research includes investigating the effects of temperature and food-availability on the growth and survival of delta smelt (Hypomesus transpacificus). While there are many potential causes for the decline in delta smelt population abundances, my research focuses on changes in the Bay-Delta food web ecology and environmental parameters as potential stressors and cause for low survival of the species. The overarching goal of this research is to provide laboratory-tested data to conservation managers to aid in the restoration of the Bay-Delta food webs and ecosystem health. The funds from this scholarship will help with the cost of running the experiment at CABA.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Denise De Carion was awarded the Bob Wise Carver Scholarship, $2500.00,  from The Diablo Valley Fly Fisherman.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She currently is a PhD student in the Ecology Graduate Group with an emphasis on conservation ecology. She works in the laboratory of Peter Moyle in the department of Wildlife and Fisheries Conservation Biology. The purpose of this laboratory is the study and conservation of California’s native fish species. Here she collaborates with researchers from the U.C. Davis Suisun Marsh Fish Study. Denise has also earned a Bachelor of Science in Environmental Science from U.C. Davis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her abstract…
&lt;i&gt;The purpose of my research is to advance our knowledge and understanding of how tidal marshes in the San Francisco Estuary provide food for commercially and recreationally significant species such as Chinook salmon and striped bass, which rely on estuaries during early life stages. My approach is intended to provide a broad perspective on how fishes feed in tidal marshes and then transfer energy and nutrients to the rest of the estuary. The estuarine ecosystem is experiencing major declines among many estuarine-dependent species, and these declines are probably a symptom of a much greater problem: food availability.&lt;/i&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Myfanwy Johnson was awarded  a scholarship, $1850.00, from the Marin Rod and Gun Club.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She currently is pursuing a PhD in animal behavior in the bio-telemetry laboratory of Dr. Peter Klimley in the department of Wildlife and Fisheries Conservation Biology at U.C. Davis.  The mission of this laboratory is the utilization of state-of-art tracking technologies with geographic information systems to understand fundamental physiological, behavioral, and ecological processes.  Our studies aim to elucidate the link between an animal&#39;s behavior and its social and physical environment.Prior to coming to U.C. Davis, Myfanwy received a B.A. in Marine Science and a B.S. in Conservation and Resource Studies, both from U.C. Berkeley in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Her Abstract...&lt;i&gt;The goal of my research is to describe the differences in movement behavior between two species of native migratory fish (white sturgeon and Chinook salmon).  Both species are not only ecologically important to the Central Valley, but also belong to culturally- and economically-important recreational fisheries.  In order to assure that these fish will be here for future generations of sportsmen  and women to enjoy, it is critical that management actions reconcile the ecological success of the species with the demands of human stakeholders co-existing in the Central Valley.  A key part of achieving successful reconciliation  practices is understanding  how these fish are navigating their migratory  landscape, as well as the factors affecting  their migratory success.  My project uses acoustic telemetry to illuminate the movement patterns of salmon and white sturgeon in the Yolo Bypass, and to examine the environmental cues they may be responding to. I hope to provide managers with reliable guidelines for implementing reconcilatory management measures.  A CABA scholarship will help by providing the funds necessary to purchase field equipment and to analyze tissue samples from tagged fish, both of which are vital to the success of my research.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Patrick Grof-Tiza received a scholarship,1850.00, from the Marin Rod and Gun Club.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patrick is a PhD candidate in the Ecology graduate group. He is co-advised by Dr. Rick Karban and Dr. Marcel Holyoak in the departments of Entomology and Environmental Science and Policy respectively. Patrick also has earned a Master of Science degree in Ecology from U.C. Davis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
His abstract…&lt;i&gt;Dragonflies and damselflies (collectively odontes) are important food resources for fish in many aquatic systems. My research will investigate how physical defenses of riparian plants can facilitate molting odonates and increase their likelihood of survival. Maintaining high populations of aquatic insects including odonates can improve fish health and increase reproductive output. The CABA scholarship will allow me to purchase materials to test my hypothesis. This work could potentially lead to a strategy to increase the abundance and quality of food resources for fish and inform riparian restoration efforts.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grace Ha was awarded a scholarship, $1500.00, from the Fly Fishers of Davis.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Grace is a PhD candidate in the Ecology Graduate group here at U.C. Davis. She is advised by Dr. Susan Williams in the department of Evolution and Ecology and is associated with the Bodega Marine Laboratory. The focus of the laboratory is the study of seagrass, algae and coral reek systems in the near shore. Prior to coming to U.C. Davis, Grace earned a Bachelor of Science in biology from Cornell University in 2010. Grace was also a Fulbright Scholar in South Korea studying the ecological knowledge of traditional diving women (haenyeo).   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Her abstract…&lt;i&gt;I study how prey species use color to camouflage in eelgrass, and how the visual abilities of surfperch predators shape those adaptations. This is important because eelgrass is recognized as a nursery habitat for species such as salmon, rockfish, herring, and surfperch, but we do not fully understand how this is. Focusing on color as an element of habitat structure, I am studying an aspect of eelgrass ecology that is related to water clarity and nutrient concentrations through the underwater light environment. Given the effect of pollution and terrestrial runoff on these environmental factors, my research is directly relevant and beneficial to sport and commercial fisheries because it could inform how these issues affect eelgrass food webs and the fish they support.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 14:49:03 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2015/04/22/CABA-announces-scholarship-winners-2015/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2015/04/22/CABA-announces-scholarship-winners-2015/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CABA announces scholarships for 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Open to U.C. Davis graduate and undergraduate* students working on Fisheries Biology and/or Riparian or Limnetic Ecology benefiting California&#39;s recreational fisheries.  Funds are awarded directly to the student and may be used for any research-related purpose, including supplies, travel, equipment, salary support, fees, etc.  For additional information and application package click here &lt;a href=&quot;/media/news/2015_caba_scholarship_application.doc&quot;&gt;2015 Scholarship Application&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please email applications to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jlboulanger@ucdavis.edu&quot;&gt;Joyce Boulanger&lt;/a&gt;, jlboulanger@ucdavis.edu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All applications must be submitted by Friday, January 30, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Only the Bob Bittner Scholarship is open to both graduate and undergraduate students in good standing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clubs’ scholarship committees are looking for proposals which have clear relevance to sport fishing in California. Click here for previous years winning abstracts...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
This years scholarships are sponsored by the following sports fishing groups...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img alt=&quot;Marin Rod and Gun Club (MRGC)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Marin Rod and Gun Club&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt; is offering two scholarships of &lt;b&gt;$1500.00 each.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img alt=&quot;California Fly Fishers Unlimited (CFFU)&quot; src=&quot;/media//news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;California Fly Fishers Unlimited&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt; are offering the Bob Bittner Scholarship of &lt;b&gt;$2500.00.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img alt=&quot;Fly Fishers of Davis&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Fly Fishers of Davis&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt; are offering a scholarship of &lt;b&gt;$1500.00.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img alt=&quot;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen (DVFF)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt; are offering the Bob Wisecarver Scholarship of &lt;b&gt;$2500.00.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 18:40:45 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2015/04/21/CABA-announces-scholarship-for-2015/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2015/04/21/CABA-announces-scholarship-for-2015/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2014 Scholarships Available EXTENDED DEADLINE for turning in scholarship applications Tuesday February 18 , 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
Open to U.C. Davis graduate and undergraduate* students working on &lt;b&gt;Fisheries Biology&lt;/b&gt; and/or &lt;b&gt;Riparian&lt;/b&gt; or &lt;b&gt;Limnetic Ecology benefiting California&#39;s recreational fisheries&lt;/b&gt;.  Funds are awarded directly to the student and may be used for any research-related purpose, including supplies, travel, equipment, salary support, fees, etc.  For additional information and application package click &lt;a href=&quot;/media/news/2014_caba_scholarship_app.docx&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; Please email applications to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:vewhitworth@ucdavis.edu&quot;&gt;Victoria Whitworth&lt;/a&gt;, vewhitworth@ucdavis.edu.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All applications must be submitted by Tuesday, February 18, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;* Only the Bob Bittner Scholarship is open to both graduate and undergraduate students in good standing.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clubs’ scholarship committees are looking for proposals which have clear relevance to sport fishing in California. Click &lt;a href=&quot;/news/2012/04/18/Abstracts-of-the-2012-Scholarship-Winners&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for previous years winning abstracts...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
This years scholarships are sponsored by the following sports fishing groups...&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen (DVFF)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Bob Wisecarver Scholarship, Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen&lt;/b&gt;,&lt;i&gt;one grant of $2500.00.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Marin Rod and Gun Club (MRGC)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Marin Rod and Gun Club Scholarships&lt;/b&gt;,&lt;i&gt;two grants of $1500.00 each.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;California Fly Fishers Unlimited (CFFU)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Bob Bittner Scholarship, California Fly Fishers Unlimited&lt;/b&gt;,&lt;i&gt;one grant of $2600.00.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Fly Fishers of Davis&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fly Fishers of Davis&lt;/b&gt;,&lt;i&gt;one scholarship of &lt;b&gt;$1500.00.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 10:25:59 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2014/02/13/2014-scholarships-available-extended-deadline-2014/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2014/02/13/2014-scholarships-available-extended-deadline-2014/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2013 Scholarships Available</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
Open to UC Davis graduate and undergraduate students working on Fisheries Biology and/or Riparian or Limnetic Ecology benefiting California&#39;s recreational fisheries.  Funds are awarded directly to the student and may be used for any research-related purpose, including supplies, travel, equipment, salary support, fees, etc. The clubs’ scholarship committees are looking for proposals which have clear relevance to sport fishing in California. Click &lt;a href=&quot;/news/2012/04/18/Abstracts-of-the-2012-Scholarship-Winners&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for previous years winning abstracts... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/fly_fishers_of_davis.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;California Fly fishers Unlimited&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Bob Bittner Scholarship&lt;/b&gt;,&lt;i&gt;one grant of &lt;b&gt;$2500.00.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (California Fly Fishers Unlimited)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen (DVFF)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Bob Wisecarver Scholarship&lt;/b&gt;,&lt;i&gt;one grant of $2500.00.&lt;/i&gt; (Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Marin Rod and Gun Club (MRGC)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Marin Rod and Gun Club Scholarships&lt;/b&gt;,&lt;i&gt;two grants of $1500.00 each.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt; 
For additional information and application package click &lt;a href=&quot;scholarship_app_2014.doc&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;
Please email applications to Victoria Whitworth, vewhitworth@ucdavis.edu
All applications must be submitted by &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thursday, January 31, 2013&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 10:32:42 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2013/12/13/2013-Scholarships-Available/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2013/12/13/2013-Scholarships-Available/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Abstracts of the 2013 Scholarship Winners</title>
        <description>&lt;section&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Marin Rod and Gun Club (MRGC)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Daniel Nylen&lt;/b&gt; was awarded one of two scholarships from the Marin Rod and Gun Club.  He is a master’s student in the Hydrologic Science Graduate Group under Dr. John Largier (UCD Bodega Marine Lab). &lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Effects of Mouth Closure Dynamics and Lagoon Hydrodynamics on Salmonid Habitat Conditions in Scott Creek Estuary, California. &lt;/i&gt;My work investigates patterns in the relationship between freshwater and ocean forces in controlling mouth closure dynamics in small bar-built estuaries typical of the California coast, and to assess to what extend these dynamics drive the hydrological state (in terms of lagoon water level, temperature, salinity, and oxygen) of the estuary, with an eye towards identifying implications for endangered native populations of steelhead and coho that use these important ecosystems as nursery habitat.  Scholarship funds would aid in obtaining the necessary equipment, including time-lapse cameras and water level sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;California Fly Fishers Unlimited (CFFU)&quot; src=&quot;/media//news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rosemary Hartman&lt;/b&gt; was awarded one of two scholarships from the Marin Rod and Gun Club. She is a doctoral candidate in the Ecology Graduate Group and is based in the lab of Dr. Sharon Lawler in the UC Davis Department of Entomology.  Rosemary was awarded the Bob Bittner scholarship in 2012 by the California Fly Fishers Unlimited club.  &lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Behavior Mechanisms of Coexistence Between the Threatened Cascades Frog and Stocked Trout.&lt;/i&gt; Fish stocked in mountain lakes for recreational fisheries provide important resources for rural economies and wilderness conservation.  However, the fish are an introduced predator that can threaten the native community.  I am studying ways in which native species adapt to fish introductions, both through behavioral changes and indirect interactions.  I have been working with the California Department of Fish and Wildlife to use my findings to help inform stocking decisions so recreational fisheries can be balanced with biodiversity concerns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen (DVFF)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sarah Wheeler&lt;/b&gt; was awarded the Bob Wisecarver scholarship from the DiabloValley Fly Fishermen club.  She is a doctoral candidate in the UC Davis Joint Doctorate Program in Ecology with San Diego State University under Dr. Todd Anderson, Dept. of Biology, San Diego State University.  Sarah also conducts research at the UCD Bodega Marine Lab.&lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Causes and Consequences of Variation in Larval Traits: A Comparison of Alternative Life History Strategies in Rockfishes.&lt;/i&gt;  Understanding the conditions conducive to the recruitment of coastal marine fishes is critical to improve the predictive ability of fisheries management.  The primary objective of my research is to better understand the recruitment of rockfishes by evaluating the biological and oceanographic factors that affect early life stages.  My research evaluates how differential maternal investment, life history strategies, and seasonal timing of birth affect larval condition and survival.  As part of this study, I will characterize the process of settlement and evaluate whether recruitment limitation in this system is driven by coastal oceanography or other factors.   
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 14:13:40 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2013/05/21/Abstracts-of-the-2013-Scholarship-Winners/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2013/05/21/Abstracts-of-the-2013-Scholarship-Winners/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2012 Coastwide Salmonid Genetics Meeting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
The Coastwide Salmonid Genetics Meeting is a biennial forum for presenting advances in genetic techniques as well as empirical genetic research involving salmonids. This conference aims to promote and further improve use of molecular techniques in conservation and restoration of salmonid biodiversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The 2012 meeting will be held from July 9th to July 12th at the Davis campus of the University of California. &lt;i&gt;This meeting is hosted by the Genomic Variation Laboratory in the Department of Animal Science.&lt;/i&gt;
For more information… &lt;a href=&quot;http://animalscience.ucdavis.edu/Coastwide&quot;&gt;http://animalscience.ucdavis.edu/Coastwide&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 08:45:57 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2012/05/17/Coastwide-Salmonid-Genetics-Meeting/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2012/05/17/Coastwide-Salmonid-Genetics-Meeting/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Abstracts of the 2012 Scholarship Winners</title>
        <description>&lt;section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rob Lusardi&lt;/b&gt; was awarded one of two scholarships from the &lt;b&gt;Marin Rod and Gun Club&lt;/b&gt;. He is a doctoral student under Drs. Peter Moyle and Jeffrey Mount and works at the UC Davis Center for Watershed Sciences.  &lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Spatial Proximity to Source Springs: Effects of Habitat and Resources on Steelhead Growth.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
Spring-fed rivers are rarely studied ecosystems, but offer a high intrinsic potential for Pacific salmonid recovery due to their unique habitat conditions. Spatial proximity to spring sources may indirectly benefit juvenile steelhead growth through changes in both water temperature and inorganic nitrate concentrations; the latter strongly affecting functional habitat and resource benefits. This proposal aims to understand the physical and ecological mechanisms contributing to steelhead growth in spring-fed rivers in order to conserve this imperiled species and its habitat for future generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Emily Peffer&lt;/b&gt; was awarded one of two scholarships from the &lt;b&gt;Marin Rod and Gun Club&lt;/b&gt;. She is a doctoral candidate under Dr. Truman Young in the UC Davis Department of Plant Sciences and a member of the Conservation Management Program. &lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Implications of Riparian Restoration to Macrophyte Communities.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
Riparian restoration is a widely accepted method for improving stream fisheries, particularly by providing temperature-cooling shade. Restoration often involves removing invasive riparian species and planting natives which decrease or increase, respectively, light available to stream beds. Emily’s research studies how altered light levels impact growth, competition and invasion potential of aquatic plants.  Aquatic plants provide habitat for invertebrates and other prey for fish, but too much aquatic vegetation can smother spawning habitat and slow stream flows. Therefore, understanding how aquatic plant communities respond to riparian restoration is important for fisheries management. Funding will help pay for supplies for her experiments.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Anna Steel&lt;/b&gt; was awarded the &lt;b&gt;Bob Wisecarver scholarship from the Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen&lt;/b&gt; club. She is a doctoral candidate working in the Biotelemetry Laboratory under Dr. Peter Klimley of the Department of Wildlife, Fish and Conservation Biology at UC Davis.&lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Largemouth Bass in the Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
Anna’s research uses ultrasonic telemetry to examine the behavior and role of largemouth bass in the Delta ecosystem to predict how the fish may respond to future changes in management practices.  The largemouth is an introduced predator which plays a dominant role in structuring shallow-water communities where it exists, and is also a much-loved sport fish which draws thousands of people to the Delta each year.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The funds from this scholarship will be used to finalize her data collection, provide support and software for the data analysis and allow her to attend local and regional conferences to share her work with managers and fellow scientists. 
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rosemary Hartman&lt;/b&gt; was awarded the &lt;b&gt;Bob Bittner scholarship from California Fly Fishers Unlimited&lt;/b&gt;.  She is a doctoral student in the laboratory of Dr. Sharon Lawler in the UC Davis Department of Entomology.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mechanisms of coexistence between recreational fisheries and native amphibians.
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;Fish stocked in mountain lakes for recreational fisheries provide important resources for rural economies and wilderness conservation.  However, the fish are an introduced predator that can threaten the native community.  Rosemary is studying ways in which native species adapt to fish introductions, both through behavioral changes and differential use of microhabitat that may allow them to coexist.  She has been working with the California Department of Fish and Game to use her findings to help inform stocking decisions so recreational fisheries can be balanced with biodiversity concerns. 


&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 15:58:09 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2012/04/18/Abstracts-of-the-2012-Scholarship-Winners/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2012/04/18/Abstracts-of-the-2012-Scholarship-Winners/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CABA announces the 2012 sportsman club scholarship award winners</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
CABA and U.C. Davis would like to thank the Marin Rod and Gun Club, Diablo Valley Fly Fishers and California Fly Fishers Unlimited for providing generous support to U.C. Davis students who are involved in aquatic animal research in California. This research provides benefits to recreational fishers as well as furthering the knowledge of California&#39;s diverse aquatic ecosystems.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Link to winning abstracts is at the bottom of this page.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img alt=&quot;Marin Rod and Gun Club (MRGC)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/marin_rod_and_gun_club.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marinrodandgunclub.com&quot;&gt;Marin Rod and Gun Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; 
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Marin Rod and Gun Club Scholarship - Awarded to Rob Lusardi and Emily Peffer.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The Marin Rod and Gun Club (MRGC) sponsored two $1,500 scholarships for graduate students conducting research in the areas of fisheries biology and/or riparian or limnetic ecology benefiting California’s recreational fisheries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img alt=&quot;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen (DVFF)&quot; src=&quot;/media/news/diablo_valley_fly_fishermen.png&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.diablovalleyflyfish.org&quot;&gt;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;      
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bob Wisecarver Scholarship - Awarded to Anna Steel&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Diablo Valley Fly Fishermen (DVFF) sponsored this $2,000 scholarship in support of graduate students conducting research in the areas of fisheries biology and/or riparian or limnetic ecology benefiting California’s recreational fisheries.  DVFF is one of the largest fly fishing clubs in the state of California and has had a special interest in promoting all fisheries conservation issues since its founding in 1968. The scholarship is named for Mr. Bob Wisecarver, the first president of the club and a well-known conservationist himself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image_wrapper left&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;gallery&quot; href=&quot;/media/news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img alt=&quot;California Fly Fishers Unlimited (CFFU)&quot; src=&quot;/media//news/california_fly_fishers_unlimited.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;California Fly Fishers Unlimited (CFFU), Bob Bittner Scholarship One $2,500 Scholarship&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cffu.org&quot;&gt;California Fly Fishers Unlimited&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bob Bittner Scholarship - Awarded to Rosemary Hartman&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;California Fly Fishers Unlimited (CFFU) sponsored this $2,800 scholarship for juniors, seniors, and graduate students conducting research on fisheries biology and/or riparian or limnetic ecology benefitting California’s recreational fisheries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/news/2012/04/18/Abstracts-of-the-2012-Scholarship-Winners&quot;&gt;Abstracts of the 2012 Scholarship Winners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 15:57:09 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2012/04/18/CABA-announces-the-2012-sportsman-club-scholarship-winners/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://caba.ucdavis.edu/news/2012/04/18/CABA-announces-the-2012-sportsman-club-scholarship-winners/</guid>
        
        <category>Rugby</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
